Created By befirelast@pt.sjtu
Created time 11.07.04 10:06:07
根据真实事件改编
只有死者才能看到战争终结 　　　　　　　――柏拉图
索马利亚-东非，1992年
多年来的部落战争，造成史无前例的饥荒
三十万人死于饥荒
势力最强大的军阀艾迪德掌控了首都摩加迪休
他抢走国际组织运送的粮食，利用饥荒做为他的武器
他的恶行引起公愤
两万名美国海军陆战队员协助运送粮食并维持治安
1993年4月
艾迪德一等到美军撤退
便立刻向联合国和平部队宣战
艾迪德的民兵在6月屠杀了24名巴基斯坦士兵
并开始攻击美国人员
八月底美军派遣精英部队
陆军反恐怖组织部队、游骑兵部队 及一六○特种作战航空营
前往摩加迪休推翻艾迪德政权，重建治安
任务原定为3星期结束
但是六星期后华府失去耐心
【 黑 鹰 坠 落 】
星期六-1993年10月2日
红十字会粮食分发中心
那里
There.
九点钟方向有武装车
Technicals, nine o'clock.
该死，你看到吗？
Oh, shit! Did you see that?
九点钟方向有平民遭到攻击
Chief, we got unarmed civilians getting shot down here at nine o'clock.
收到了，但我们不能干涉
I got it, Matt. I don't think we can touch this.
这些粮食属于艾迪德
This food is the property of Mohamed Farrah Aidid!
快滚回家吧
Go back to your homes!
这是超级64号
Command, Super 64,,,
民兵在粮食分发中心扫射平民
,,,We got militia shooting civilians at the food distribution center,
请准许攻击
Request permission to engage.
你遭到炮火攻击吗？
Super 64, are you taking fire? Over,
没有
Negative, command,
这是联合国辖区，我们不能干涉
U,N, 's jurisdiction, 64, We cannot intervene,
-返回基地 -收到
-Return to base, Over, -Roger,
64号返回基地
64 returning,
摩加迪休，巴卡拉市集，艾迪德势力范围
可以走了，奥图先生
Ready, Mr, Atto,
他要走了
Leaving.
先生
Sir,
继续开
Keep Driving!
我会迟到
I'm going to be late,
待会再打给你
Call you back,
盖瑞森将军
General Garrison?
谢了，我有了
No, thanks. I got one.
这是古巴雪茄
But these are Cuban.
上好的雪茄
Bolivar Belicoso.
这也是
So is this.
迈阿密雪茄没古巴雪茄赞
Miami, my friend, is not Cuba.
你们老是抓不到艾迪德
I see not catching Aidid is becoming a routine.
这次我们要抓的是你
We weren't trying to catch Aidid. We were trying to catch you.
我？
Me?
我有这么重要吗？
But am I that important?
没有吧
I hardly think so.
-你只是个生意人 -只想混口饭吃
-You're just a businessman. -Trying to make a living.
你贩卖枪械给艾迪德的民兵
Yeah. Selling guns to Aidid's militia.
你来了多久？
You've been here, what?
6个星期？
Six weeks?
6星期来你一直想抓到他
Six weeks you are trying to catch the general.
到处张帖悬赏海报
You put up reward posters.
两万五千美元，你想演“终结追杀令”吗？
$25,000. What is this? Gunfight at the K.O. Corral?
是“绝命追杀令”
It's the O.K. Corral.
你以为把我抓来他就会自首？
Do you think bringing me in will make him suddenly come to you?
乖乖束手就擒？
Make him more agreeable?
你知道他在哪里
You know where he sleeps.
你资助他的一切，包括民兵
You pay for his beds, much less his militia.
我们逮不到他就不走
We're not leaving Somalia till we find him.
我们一定会逮到他
And we will find him.
别以为我从小没自来水喝
Don't think because I grew up without running water...
就是个笨蛋
...l am simple, General.
我对历史很了解
I do know something about history.
你看到吗？我们在创造明天
See all this? It's simply shaping tomorrow.
一个没有阿肯色州白小子的明天
A tomorrow without a lot of Arkansas white boys' ideas in it.
我来自德州
Well, I wouldn't know about that. I'm from Texas.
盖将军，你们不该来这儿
Mr. Garrison, I think you shouldn't have come here.
这是内战
This is civil war.
这是我们的战争
This is our war.
不是你们的
Not yours.
三十万人死亡
300,000 dead and counting.
这不是战争，这是种族屠杀
That's not a war, Mr. Atto. That's genocide.
喝茶吧
Now, you enjoy that tea, you hear?
你觉得他怎样？
How'd he strike you?
彬彬有礼、冷酷无情
Urbane, sophisticated, cruel.
他是一条大鱼
Yeah, he's a good catch.
时间一久艾迪德就会感到受制
lt'll take time, but Aidid will feel the loss.
我们没有太多时间
I'm not sure time is something we got in great supply.
这比伊拉克的情形更复杂
This isn't lraq, you know. Much more complicated than that.
但华府官员可不这么想
Boss, most of Washington might disagree.
他们每天都要我们提出报告
They've been calling for situation reports every morning this week.
你就说战争一触即发
Well, tell them the situation is fragile.
摩加迪休机场 美国陆军联合作战指挥部
各位，我是猫王威考
Ladies and gentlemen, I'm Cliff "Elvis" Wolcott,
本班机的机长
I'll be your pilot today,
这架黑鹰直升机是非吸烟区
Federal regulations designate this a non-smoking Black Hawk helicopter.
本航空公司的会员可以累积100点的哩程
Those in Mogadishu frequent flyer program will earn 100 free credits.
呕吐袋就放在前座的椅背
And as always, the air sickness bags are in the seatback in front of you.
一号引擎正常，检查二号引擎
Number one indications are good, Cliff. Put her on two.
没问题
You're still clear,
这是64号，使用高频无线电
61, this is 64, Go to UHF secure,
我有坏消息
I've got some bad news.
礼车是一个字，别跟我罗唆
"Limo" is a word, Durant. I don't want to hear about it.
那是缩写，不是一个字
It is not a Word, It's an abbreviation of a Word,
那是常用语
"Limo" is a word in common usage.
拼字游戏的规则接受常用语
That is the key phrase in Scrabble, my good friend. Common usage.
字典查不到就不算
If it's not in the dictionary it doesn't count!
字典查不到也算
It doesn't have to be in the dictionary!
字典查不到就不算
It does have to be in the dictionary!
等我回基地就把这个字剔除
When we get back to the base, it's coming off.
你敢我就扁你，听到吗？
You touch my "limo" and I'll spank you, Nightstalker,
你有种扁我才怪
Yeah, promises.
好美的海滩
That's a nice beach down there.
海水怎样？
How's the water?
很暖和，到处都是鲨鱼
Yeah, it's nice and warm. And it's loaded with sharks.
-名字 -陶德
-Name. -Todd.
-姓氏 -贝克朋
-Last name. -Blackburn.
名字是陶德
First name, Todd.
-怎样？ -什么怎样？
-So, what's it like? -What's what like?
摩加迪休，战事
Mogadishu. The fighting.
-兵籍号码
-Serial number. -72163427.
大家都简称为摩加，不会说摩加迪休
Firstly, it's "the Mog" or simply "Mog." No one calls it Mogadishu here.
我没有打仗，别问我
Secondly, I wouldn't know about the fighting, so don't ask.
为什么？
Why not?
我叫你别问我
Didn't I just say, "Don't ask"?
你像个小孩，我解释给你听
You look like you're about 12, so let me explain something to you.
我有一种特殊才能，不必打仗
I have a rare and mysterious skill that precludes me from doing missions.
打字
Typing.
-你会吗？ -不会
-Can you type? -No.
-生日 -1975年2月27日
-Date of birth. -2-27-75.
18岁
我是来踢爆坏人的
Well, I'm here to kick some ass.
回去吧
Let's bring it in,
漂亮，干得好
Nice, man! Very smooth!
一枪就射穿引擎
Single shot through the engine block.
真可惜，那辆吉普车很帅
Shit, that's a shame. That was a nice jeep.
停火
Cease fire! Cease fire!
检查武器
Check your weapons!
艾中士
Sergeant Eversmann.
我是一等兵贝克朋
Private First Class Blackburn.
什么事？
Yeah?
我来报到
Reporting for duty.
你要向毕中尉报到，他应该就在附近
Not to me. You're reporting to Lt. Beales. He should be here somewhere.
我把他交给你
Can I leave him with you?
好吧
Yeah, go ahead.
-你把枪带来了 -是，长官
-You brought your weapon. -Yes, sir.
我不累，我能练靶吗？
Want me to shoot? I'm rested.
-你几时到？ -刚才
-When did you get in? -Just now, Sergeant.
谁饿了？
Hey, who's hungry?
这算什么？纳税人出钱的狩猎大餐吗？
What is this, Sarg'nt? Another taxpayer-funded Delta safari?
-盖将军问起可别说 -我问起呢？
-Not if General Garrison is asking. -I'm asking.
用餐愉快，上尉
Have a nice meal, Captain.
-大家都在排队 -我知道
-Hey, man, there's a line. -I know.
-你这是插队 -我也知道
-Well, this isn't the back of it. -Yeah, I know.
中士
Sergeant. Sergeant.
这干嘛？
What's going on here?
我们在练靶，打到一只野猪
Some aerial target practice, sir. Didn't want to leave it behind.
我是说你的步枪
I'm talking about your weapon.
反恐怖部队也不能拿上膛的步枪到处晃
Delta or no Delta, that's a hot weapon.
你应该很清楚，枪要随时上保险
You know better than that. Safety should be on at all times on base.
这就是我的“保险”
Well, this is my safety, sir.
别管他，他两天没吃饭了
Let it go, sir. The guy hasn't eaten in a couple of days.
反恐怖部队都是一群蛮牛
You Delta boys are a bunch of undisciplined cowboys.
让我告诉你
Let me tell you something, Sarg'nt.
到了前线你需要游骑兵支援
When we get on a five-yard line, you're going to need my Rangers.
你最好有点团队精神
Y'all better learn to be team players.
我说完了
We're done here.
说呀，你说这是保险
Speak up. You say this is your safety?
这是我的靴子
Well, this is my boot, son.
小心我用这只靴子把你踢爆
And it will fit up your ass with the proper amount of force.
-这算新泽西口音吗？ -拜托，我很努力耶
-ls that a Jersey accent? -I'm trying to do this, give me a break.
把太阳眼镜脱掉
Take those sunglasses off.
反恐怖部队爱戴名牌墨镜，那是他们的事
Delta wants to wear Oakleys, that's their business.
别让我再看到你戴
I don't want to see them on you again.
那是一把上膛的步枪？
Is that a hot Weapon?
你下了吗？
Is that your move?
手还没离棋啊？
Is my hand on the piece?
再下三步我就赢了
I can mate you in three whatever you do.
你自己最好小心点
I'd keep my eye on that queen before counseling others.
有种就放马过来
Well, she's just lying in wait.
唉
Yikes.
你画得越来越好了
It's good. You're really improving.
不过我有一个建议
If I may make a suggestion-- Observation.
说吧
Go ahead.
-这是童话故事，对吧？ -没错
-It's a children's book, right? -Right.
这会把小孩子吓得屁滚尿流
They are not supposed to scare the living shit out of the children.
骑士正要屠龙
This is the part of the story where our knight is slaying the dragon.
本来就很可怕，而且我女儿最喜欢了
That's scary. Besides, my daughter loves this stuff.
我以为你上礼拜就画完了
Thought you finished that last week.
你说完了吗？
You done?
就快冲到十码线了
Hey, we are at the 10-yard line here, men.
明白吗？
You understand?
你会数吗？1、2、3
Can you count? One, two, ten.
我的后卫呢？
Okay? Where are my running backs?
Where are my running backs?
我没看到你做礼拜
Hey, I didn't see you at church on Sunday.
你有别的事吗？
You had something more important to do?
礼拜天一定要做礼拜
Not on Sunday, you don't. Not anymore.
别给我落跑，了解吗？
I will make you believe, you understand?
很好笑，呼吓
Pretty funny, hoo-ah?
你学得很像，很像我
It was a good impression. I recognize myself.
继续吧
All right, carry on.
-我要跟你讲话 -是，长官
-I'd like a word, specialist. -Sir.
你知道谁有指挥权吧？
You understand why we have a chain of command, don't you?
知道，长官
Roger that, sir.
你敢再取笑我，我就命令你把马桶舔干净
If you ever undermine me again, you'll clean latrines with your tongue...
保证你一个月吃不下饭
...till you taste no difference between shit and French fries.
-明白吗？ -明白，长官
-Are we clear? -Hoo-ah, sir.
好吧
All right.
听好：
Listen to this:
当一个索马利亚人杀了人 他的部落就欠对方部落一百只骆驼
If one skinny kills another his clan owes the dead guy's clan a hundred camels.
一百只骆驼
A hundred camels.
我连一只都不给
Camels. I wouldn't pay one camel.
这儿的骆驼欠债一定很多
Must be a lot of fucking camel debt.
这是真的吗？
Is that really true, Lieutenant?
去问艾士官，他喜欢非洲人
Ask Sgt. Eversmann. He likes skinnies.
艾士官，那是真的吗？
Sgt. Eversmann, you really like the skinnies?
不是喜欢不喜欢的问题，我尊敬他们
It's not that I like them or I don't like them. I respect them.
你们要知道艾士官很有理想
See, what you guys fail to realize is the sergeant is a bit of an idealist.
他相信这项任务的使命，对吧，士官？
He believes in this mission down to his bones. Don't you, Sergeant?
这些人没有工作
Look, these people, they have no jobs...
没有食物、教育和未来
...no food, no education, no future.
我只是觉得我们有两个选择
I just figure that, I mean, we have two things that we can do.
帮助他们
We can help...
或是眼睁睁看着他们自相残杀
...or we can sit back and watch the country destroy itself on CNN.
对吧？
Right?
我不知道，我是来打仗的
I don't know about you guys, but I was trained to fight.
你不是吗？
Are you trained to fight, Sergeant?
我是来改善世界的
Well, I think I was trained to make a difference, Kurth.
他真的很有理想
Like the man said, he's an idealist.
等等，我最爱这一段
Oh, wait. This is my favorite part.
滚远一点
Stay aWay from the cans!
去死吧，猪头
Die, gas-pumper!
给我滚远一点
Stay aWay from those cans!
不，退后
No, no, stay back.
他的癫痫症发作了，拿东西让他咬着
He's having a seizure. Put something in his mouth.
约翰，没事了…没事了…
John, it's okay. John, it's okay. It's okay.
清晨5:45，10月3日　星期天
他没事了，不过他得退伍
Well, he'll be fine. But not in this army.
他有癫痫症，我要送他回家
He's out of the game. He's epileptic, going home.
我要你当小队长
I'm putting you in charge of his chalk.
-你有意见吗？ -没有，长官
-You got a problem with that? -No, sir.
这个责任很重大
It's a big responsibility.
你的弟兄都仰赖你
Your men will look to you to make the right decisions.
他们的命都在你手上
Their lives depend on it.
好了
All right.
-游骑兵做先锋 -勇往直前
-Rangers lead the way, sir. -All the way.
祝好运
Good luck.
哈瓦迪街，巴卡拉市集 艾迪德民兵据点
艾迪德的资深阁员今天下午三点可能要开会
A meeting of Aidid's senior cabinet may take place today at 1500 hours,
我说可能是因为…
I say "may" because we all know by now...
根据目前的情报，一切都不确定
...with the intel we get on the street, nothing is certain.
这是三方确定的情报
This is actual intel confirmed by three sources.
两名高层阁员可能会在场
Two tier-one personalities may be present:
奥玛萨拉，艾迪德的政治顾问
Omar Salad, Aidid's top political advisor...
哈珊奥威利，内政部长
...and Abdi Hassan Awale, interior minister.
他们是我们的目标
These are the guys we're after.
今天就行动
Today we go.
任务计划和以前一样
Same mission template as before.
3点45分，反恐怖部队攻击小组负责攻入敌方建筑物
1545, Assault Force Delta will infiltrate the target building...
逮捕内部所有嫌疑犯
...and seize all suspects within.
史上尉指挥的游骑兵小队
Security Force Rangers: 4 Ranger chalks, under command of Capt. Steele...
要在3点46分
...will rope in at 1546...
在目标的四个角落建立防线
...and hold a four-corner perimeter around the target building.
任何人不得进出
No one gets in or out.
撤退部队
Extraction Force:
麦奈中校的悍马车队在3点47分开进哈瓦迪街
Lt. Colonel McKnight's humvee column will drive in at 1547...
停在奥林匹克旅馆前
...on Hawlwadig Road and hold just short of the Olympic Hotel.
等待指令
Wait for the green light.
当反恐怖部队突击成功
Now once Delta gives the word...
麦中校的手下就把人犯架上车
...McKnight's column will go to the target and load the prisoners onto trucks.
把人犯架上车后
lmmediately after the prisoners are loaded...
游骑兵队员立刻到目标大楼集合
...the four Ranger chalks will collapse back to the target building...
一起上悍马车队
...load up on humvees...
地面部队就一路赶回基地
...and the entire ground force will exfil the 3 miles back to base.
行动时间只有半小时
Mission time, no longer than 30 minutes.
我请求调动装甲车和AC-130炮艇机支援
Now, I had requested light armor and AC-130 Spectre gunships...
但华府却不同意
...but Washington, in all its wisdom, decided against this.
太显眼了
Too high-profile.
准备多管机枪的黑鹰直升机
So Black Hawks and Little Birds will provide the air cover...
将提供空中支援
...with miniguns and 2.75 rockets.
哈上校
Colonel Harrell.
马上校负责调派空中支援
In the C-2 bird, Colonel Matthews will coordinate the air mission...
我负责指挥地面部队
...and I will coordinate ground forces.
马上校
Colonel Matthews.
任务执行代号是艾琳
Mission launch code word is lrene.
有问题吗？
Questions?
目标是哪栋建筑？
Which building is it, sir?
巴卡拉市集附近的建筑物
We're confirming that now. Somewhere near the Bakara market.
我不能决定他们在哪里开会
I don't choose the time or place of their meetings.
我没这么说
I didn't say a word, sir.
大家听好，你们到了市集
Make no mistake, once you're in the Bakara market...
就等于进入敌区
...you're in an entirely hostile district.
千万别低估敌人实力
Don't underestimate their capabilities.
进入市集之前都不是敌区
We'll be in friendly neighborhoods before we hit the market...
千万切记交战法则，遭到攻击才能反击
...so remember the rules of engagement: No one fires unless fired upon.
完成任务吧
Now, let's go get this thing done.
祝好运，各位
Good luck, gentlemen.
怎么了？你不满意吗？
What's the matter, Danny? Something you don't like?
没有C-炮艇机，白天出任务
No Spectre gunships, daylight instead of night...
敌人的精神在下午特别亢奋
...afternoon when they're all fucked up on khat...
那儿又是火力集中的敌区
...only part of the city Aidid can mount a counter-attack on short notice....
-我有什么不满意的？ -人生不如意十有八九
-What's not to like? -Life's imperfect.
你们在半空中只是不如意
For you two, circling above it at 500 feet, it's imperfect.
我们在地面就苦不堪言
Down in the street, it's unforgiving.
搞什么？
What the fuck, Smith?
-怎样？ -什么怎样？
-Well? -Well, what?
我们要行动吗？
We going?
-我干嘛告诉你 -你就是要说
-Why should I tell you that? -Because I'm me.
对，下午三点，市中心
Yeah. 3:00. Downtown.
-巴卡拉市集 -好耶
-Bakara market. -All right.
小史，我要你全力支持我
Listen, Smith, I need you to back me up out there today, all right?
提高警觉
Keep sharp.
遵命，艾士官
Yes, sir, Sergeant Eversmann.
这次行动是小意思啦
Ev, it's going to be nothing, man.
小意思
Nothing.
关键是磨咖啡豆，不能磨得太细或太粗
It's all in the grind, Sizemore. Can't be too fine, can't be too coarse.
这是一种技巧
This, my friend, is a science.
我可是相信征兵广告的那种人
You're looking at the guy that believed the commercials.
尽忠报国
About "be all you can be."
但是我在波湾战争都在煮咖啡
I made coffee through Desert Storm.
在巴拿马也煮咖啡，别的游骑兵队员
I made coffee through Panama, while everyone else got to fight...
都出生入死
...got to be a Ranger.
我却只能煮黑咖啡，替别人拿奶精
Now it's "Grimesy, black, one sugar" or "Grimesy, got a powdered anywhere?"
-怎么了？ -乒乓球受伤
-What happened to you? -Ping-Pong accident.
什么？
What?
猜怎么着？
So guess what.
你的愿望实现了，你要出任务
Your wish has been granted. You're going out today.
少唬烂我
You're fucking me.
你要代替我负责有装备枪榴弹的M-步枪
You're taking my place assisting the 60 gunner.
艾士官叫你收拾好装备
Sergeant Eversmann said to get your stuff and get ready.
你想要打仗，不是吗？
It's what you wanted, isn't it?
是啊
Oh, yeah.
当然了
Hell, yeah.
葛姆，跟着瓦德给他弹药
Grimesy, stick with Waddell and give him ammo when he needs it.
-呼吓？ -呼吓
-Hoo-ah? -Hoo-ah.
别担心，索利亚人的枪法都很烂
I wouldn't worry about that. Generally speaking, Somalis can't shoot for shit.
小心别被他们的石头K到就行
Just watch out for the sammys throwing the rocks, and you'll be fine.
会好玩的
Might even be fun.
让反恐怖部队打头阵，我们只要支援他们
D-boys do their thing now. All we got to do is cover them.
直升机也会掩护我们
Choppers going to cover us, and we'll be all right.
我知道我是第一次当小队长
Look, you guys, this is my first time as chalk leader...
但我们不是第一次出任务
...but, this isn't our first time out together. This is serious.
我们是游骑兵，不是预备军官
We're Rangers, not some sorry-ass JROTC.
我们是精英部队
We're elite.
大家要好好表现
Let's act like it out there. Hoo-ah?
有问题吗？
Any questions?
我们不会有事的
We're going to be okay.
收拾好装备，出动吧
Grab your gear. Let's move out.
你不需要水壶，很快就会回来
You're not going to need that, dude. We're not out there long enough.
那也用不着
You won't need that, either.
天黑前就会回来
We'll be back before dark.
你不如多带大麻和啤酒
You might as well take dope and beer instead.
什么？
What?
弹药啦，多带弹药啦
Ammo, dude. Take ammo.
你身上有五十磅的装备
Let me tell you something, Grimes. You got 50 pounds of gear.
不必多加十二磅
You don't need another 12.
背这么重想逃命都逃不了
I don't know about you, I don't plan on getting shot running away.
我还是要穿防弹背心
Well, I better keep mine in.
葛姆
Grimes.
最重要的是
Most important thing:
跟着大家射击的方向开枪
Remember, when everyone is shooting, shoot in the same direction.
你看，他在靴子帖上血型
Look at this. He's taping his blood type to his boots.
-触霉头 -很聪明
-That's bad luck. -No, it's smart.
反恐怖部队都这么做
All Delta do that.
写遗书也很倒霉
That's bad luck too, man.
快走吧
Come on, let's go.
幸好你不是左撇子
It's a good thing you're right-handed, Adonis.
-要不然你就没搞头了 -你真会说笑
-lf not, I don't know what you'd do. -You're a funny guy, man.
-我不替你拿遗书 -我们说好的
-I'm not taking no death letter. -We have a deal.
一小时后还给你
I'll give it to you back in an hour.
-贝克朋，你还好吧？ -我很兴奋
-Blackburn, you okay? -Excited.
这是好事我当兵就是为了打仗
In a good way. I've been training my whole life for this.
你杀过人吗？
You ever shot at anybody before?
没有
No, sir.
我也没有
Me neither.
下午2点29分
他可靠吗？
Think he's reliable?
等着瞧吧，他第一次出任务
Well, we'll see. It's his first time out.
联合行动指挥中心
-叫他把收音机关掉 -是，长官
-Tell him to turn his damn radio off. -Yes, sir.
叫他把收音机关掉
Tell him to turn his radio off.
阿弟，把收音机关掉
Abdi, you need to turn your radio off.
这是史黛芬和蓝迪，请留言，谢谢
Hi, You've reached Stephanie and Randy, leave us a message, Thank you,
老婆，是我，你在吗？
Hey, baby, it's me, Are you there?
你在的话就快接
Pick up if you're there,
我只是打来看你好不好
I'm just calling to make sure everything's all right.
过两小时再打给你
I'll call you in a couple hours.
你最好别睡着了
You'd better not be sleeping.
该你了，蓝迪
Your move, Randy.
我好想你
I'm missing you,
我爱你
I love you, baby.
喂？
Hello? Hello?
谢了
Thanks, bud.
这有点好笑
You know, it's kind of funny.
洁白的沙滩，灿烂的阳光
Beautiful beach, beautiful sun.
几乎是一个好地方
Could almost be a good place to visit.
几乎
Almost.
你认为我们不该来
You don't think we should be here.
你知道我怎么想吗？我怎么想不重要
You know what I think? It don't really matter what I think.
第一颗子弹从你头上呼啸而过
Once that first bullet goes past your head, politics and all that shit...
那些狗屁倒灶的事都不重要
...just goes right out the window.
我只想完成任务
I just want to do it right today.
打起精神，让弟兄活着回来
Just watch your corner. Get all your men back here alive.
就是这里还是汽车抛锚？
Now, is this supposed to be the place, or did his car just take a dump?
阿弟，请回答
Abdi, come in,
你听到吗？这是目标吗？
Abdi, can you hear me? Is this the place?
阿弟
Abdi, come in,
听到吗？
Can you hear me? Abdi,
请回答，是这里吗？
Abdi, come in, Is this the place?
我右手边，咖啡厅楼上
To my right side, above the cafe.
他说就是这里
He says this is the building,
他确定？
He's certain?
阿弟，你要确定才行
Abdi, you need to be sure,
你确定？
Are you sure?
目标在我左边两条街口外
Well, it's down the road, two blocks over on my left.
不过民兵太多了
But there's too many militia.
我一靠近他们就会开枪
If I go closer, they might shoot me,
他说目标在两个街口外
NoW he's saying the building's a couple blocks doWn,,,
不过他怕对方会向他开枪
...but if he's seen outside it, he'll be shot.
我才会宰了他
I'll fucking shoot him myself.
叫他把车子停在目标门口
Tell him I want his skinny ass parked in front of the building.
他不去就拿不到钱
He's not getting paid till he does exactly that.
离目标三哩，不要走小路
Three miles to the target. We're never off the main roads.
到了圆环先向北然后往东
At K-four traffic circle, we turn north, then east on National...
在那儿等候劫出人犯
...and we wait until extraction of prisoners is complete here.
然后全队开进
Then we roll up in force on Hawlwadig...
把人犯跟地面部队载回来
...load the prisoners, the assault-blocking forces and bring them back.
一小时后回基地
Home in an hour. Okay?
敌人会反击，那儿就像西部电影一样
There will be some shooting. Bakara market is the Wild West.
小心开枪，那儿有平民
But be careful what you shoot at. People do live there.
呼吓
Hoo-ah.
上一个线民玩俄罗斯轮盘搁屁了
Last one of these guys shot himself in the head playing Russian roulette.
长官，他停车了
Sir, the vehicle is stopped,
这就是目标，他确定吗？
So this is the real deal now. He's sure this time.
-他吓得屁滚尿流 -好，好现象
-He sounds scared shitless, -Good. That's always a good sign.
这就是我们的信号
That's it, That's our signal,
好
All right.
要所有飞机离开该空域
All QRF out of the airspace.
出动快速反应部队
全体注意，艾琳，重覆，艾琳
All units, lrene. I say again, lrene.
检查完毕，B51号好了，S41号好了
Check in When ready, Barber 51 up and ready, Star 41 up and ready,
艾琳！
lrene!
收到
Copy, Irene,
出动了
Fucking lrene!
收到
Come on.
祝好运
Good luck, boys.
小心点
Be careful.
决不抛弃同胞
No one gets left behind.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
他从没来道过别
Nothing. He's just never done that before.
天杀的
Aw, fuck!
走吧
Let's go.
指崔克中士，出发吧
Sergeant Struecker. Let's roll.
两分钟
TWo minutes,
Two minutes.
他们干嘛烧轮胎？
Why are they burning tires?
通知民兵我们要来了
Signals to the militia that we're coming!
看来地面有平民
Okay, 56, looks like there's some friendlies on the ground,
我能拦截到他们的对话
Looks like I've got a tally on the voice,
一分钟
One minute.
还有一分钟
“约翰葛里辛-终极证人”
你在干嘛？
What's that for?
上次我差点把舌头咬断
Last rope, I almost bit my tongue off.
准备降落
Touching base,
两英尺、一英尺
TWo feet, one foot,,,
下午3点42分
,,,clear,
触地
小型直升机安全降落
Little birds touching doWn at target,
奥林匹克
潘下绳索
Ropes!
快…快…
Go! Go! Go!
第一小队着地，第二小队出动
Chalk One troops are on the deck, Chalk TWo deployed,
这是麦奈，地面车队接近目标
This is McKnight, Uniform 64 approaching staging area,
趴下来！趴下！
Down! Get down!
趴下！趴下！
Down! Stay down!
快趴下！
Get down! Everybody down!
你，趴下！
You, down!
趴下！
Get down!
On the floor.
快走，走！
Let's go, let's go!
葛姆，别害怕！
Grimesy! No fear!
是呀
Oh, yeah, right!
游骑兵守住防线
Rangers securing perimeter, Four corners,
中校，他们在开火
Colonel, they're shooting at us!
中校，他们朝我们开枪
那就打回去啊
Well, shoot back!
我们到地面，准备建立防线
This is 64, Chalks on the ground, going into holding pattern,
出动部队，准备建立防线
This is 62, delivered chalks, Going to cover pattern,
黑鹰直升机，请在空中掩护
Super 62, take up an overhead pattern to provide sniper cover, Over,
部队登陆，准备建立防线
This is Super 65, Chalks on the ground, going into holding pattern,
贝克朋，快下去
Go, Blackburn, go! Go!
快呀
Go, Blackburn!
RPG火箭弹
RPG!
抓紧了！
Hold on!
不！
No!
C-2，有位弟兄摔下去
C-2, We got a man fallen,
超级61号，别一直盘旋
Super-61, you're a sitting duck,
请在空中掩护我们
Take up overhead pattern to provide sniper cover, Over,
收到，我们要离开
Roger that, 61 coming out,
13组，快赶到街口北边
13, go ahead, I need you to move to the north of the street,
那儿，就在那边
Right to the north, Right there, Over,
史医官，快点
Doc! Doc Schmid!
快！
Come on!
史医官，有人受伤
Schmid, we got a man hit.
-哪里中弹？ -没有，他摔下来
-Where's he hit? -He's not. He fell.
-什么？ -他摔下来
-What? -He fell.
你怎么不开枪？
Why aren't you shooting?
他们没向我们开枪
We're not being shot at yet!
你怎么分辨？
How can you tell?
子弹咻一声代表很近
A hiss means it's close.
啪哒一声表示…
A snap means--
他们向我们开枪了
Now they're shooting at us!
杰利顿！
Galentine!
快帮我接史上尉！
Get me Captain Steele! Get me Captain Steele!
J64，这是J25，请回答
Juliet 64, this is Juliet 25. Come in. Over.
贝克朋，听得到吗？
Blackburn, can you hear me?
J64，这是25，请回答
Juliet 64, this is 25. Come in. Over.
我联络不到他
I can't get him!
J64，这是第四小队！ 有弟兄受伤！
Juliet 64, this is Chalk Four! We've got a man down!
快把他救走！
We need to get him out of here! Over.
请再说一次
This is 64. Say again, 25. Over.
有一名弟兄受伤
We've got a man doWn! Over,
别紧张，冷静点
Take a breath, 25, and calm down. Over.
-弟兄受伤 -没听到
-Man down! -Missed that, 25,
-没用 -再说一次
-Fuck it. -Say again,
我们离悍马车队很远
Matt, it's a long way to the humvees!
这儿有担架，把他抬进去
We'll get a stretcher in here. Get him to the target building.
他说什么？
What did he say?
有一名弟兄受伤倒地
Super 61, We got a man Wounded on the ground,
-担架， -快拿担架
-Stretcher! -Get me a stretcher!
快点
Come on. Stretcher.
快点…
Come on, come on!
抓住另一边
Grab this end!
走吧
Let's go!
-好 -走
-All right. -Go.
把他抬上悍马车，我们来掩护
Get him to the humvees. We'll hold down the corner.
快把他抬上车
Up to the humvees! Now!
快，快
Go! Go!
快走，快跑
Keep moving, Grimes! Run!
-安全 -走吧
-Secure! -Let's move out!
快起来，快走
Everybody up! Let's go!
走吧
Come on!
快走
Let's go! Let's move!
-葛姆，跑！ -好啦
-Grimes, run! -All right.
C-2，这是超级61号，开始盘旋
C-2, this is Super 61, beginning my orbit of the target area,
第四小队，我们快要降落
Chalk Four, clear for a clear, Coming in,
凯罗11号，这是超级61号，我掩护你们
Kilo 11, this is 61, providing cover for prisoner extract, Over,
可以行动
Kilo 64, green light.
-准备搭载人犯 -收到了
-Ready for extraction, Over, -Roger that, Will relay,
很好，逮到他们了
That's it. We got them.
准备接收人犯
Uniform 64, ready for extraction, Over,
收到了，他们下令了，快去吧
Roger that. There's the call. Let's move out!
-快去吧！ -抓紧了
-Let's move out! -Hold on.
-还要多久？ -五分钟
-How much longer? -Five minutes, sir.
-什么？ -五分钟
-What? -Five minutes.
绝对不只五分钟
Nothing takes five minutes!
他是怎么了？
What happened to him?
-他没抓到绳索摔下去 -怎么会？
-He fell! Missed the rope! -How'd he do that?
把他抬上车，帮帮忙
Put him in that humvee! Grimes, give him a hand!
走吧，快走
Let's go! Let's move it!
快，动作快点
Move, move! Come on! Move!
把他抬上去
Get him in there!
快走
Get ready to move!
快呀
Go! Everybody move! Move!
快上车
Get the fuck up!
葛姆，来呀
Grimes! Come on!
葛姆，葛姆
Grimes! Grimes!
我靠！
Fuck this!
可恶
Fuck!
快走
Let's go.
快点
Come on!
快走
Go! Move it!
快点
Move!
我要三辆悍马车后送伤兵
Romeo 64, I need to send out three humvees with a casualty.
他的伤势很重，必须立刻后送
He looks real bad. I need to evac now.
收到了
Roger that, Uniform 64.
我会派一组直升机去掩护你
We'll chop a team of gun ships to you, Over,
收到
Roger that.
我要派人掩护悍马车队
I need extra security on these humvees!
我去，我带手下去掩护他们
I'll go. I'll take my team, make sure they get back okay.
快去
Do it.
史崔克，你带领车队
Struecker, you're lead humvee.
快上车，我们要回基地
First three vehicles mount up, We're moving back to base,
走吧
Move out!
状况如何？没问题吧？
How are things going? Things okay there, Struecker?
我没时间谈
I don't want to talk about it now, Colonel!
我正在忙
I'm busy,
皮中士中弹
Sergeant Pilla's hit!
老天，他伤得好重
Christ, he's fucked up!
有人中弹吗？
Is anyone hit?
史崔克，快说
Struecker, talk to me!
是皮中士
It's Sergeant Pilla!
他的状况如何？
What's his status?
他死了
He's dead.
皮中士死了
Pilla's dead, sir,
C-2，这是麦奈，皮中士阵亡了
C-2, this is McKnight, We have a KIA Dominick Pilla, Over,
收到了
Roger that,
快接手五○机枪
Get on that 50!
快接手继续发射
Someone get on that 50!
让我来
It's mine.
三个家伙拿着火箭筒接近你
Three guys with RPGs, coming up on your side now!
稳住！
Stay with it!
我被击中了
This is 61, I'm hit, I'm hit,
超级61号被击中，威考的直升机被击中
Super 61 is hit, He is hit, Wolcott's bird is hit,
快把输油阀关掉
You want to pull those PCLs off-line or what?
好
Right, babe.
撑下去啊
Come on.
61号直升机被击中
61, going down.
61号直升机要坠毁
61 going down.
61号直升机坠毁
61 is going doWn,
超级61号直升机坠毁
Super 61 is going doWn,
61号直升机坠毁，重覆，坠毁中
61 is going doWn, I repeat, it's going doWn,
61号坠毁中
61's going doWn,
抓紧了
Hold on!
有一架黑鹰直升机坠毁了
We got a Black HaWk doWn, We got a Black HaWk doWn,
超级61号直升机坠毁在市中心
Super 61 is down. We got a bird down in the city.
61号直升机坠毁地面
Super 61 is on the deck noW,
快赶到现场抢救生还者
Get an MH-six on site. Check for survivors.
快派出搜救直升机
Send in the SAR bird.
快派地面部队前往坠机地点
I want ground forces to move and secure a new perimeter around that crash site.
你们能引导车队吗？
Can you guide the convoy in there?
没问题
Roger that,
快去呀
Well, move quick.
民兵会蜂拥而上围攻他们
The whole city will be coming down on top of them.
请试着降落在坠机地点
Star 41, come inbound and see if you can land at the crash site.
收到，马上去
Roger that, Star 41 inbound,
我们失去了先机
We just lost the initiative.
25，这是64部队
25, this is 64. Over.
25，收到
25. Over.
这是第四小队，你的小队最接近坠机地点
25, Chalk Four is closest to the crash site. Over.
64，我看不到坠机地点
64, I can't see the crash site. Over.
就在正东方，你一定看得到
25, it's due east of you. You will find it.
派人留守，率领其他人赶到坠机地点
Leave a security element in place. Take the rest of your chalk to the crash.
搜救生还者，维持安全，其它小队会跟着去
Check for survivors. Secure the area. All other chalks will follow.
你收到吗？
25, do you read me? Over.
杰利顿、史密斯
Galentine! Schmid!
去找尤利
Get Yurek.
和汤比
Get Twombly.
有一架黑鹰直升机坠毁
Hey, there's a Black Hawk down.
汤比和尼森留守
Twombly, Nelson, stay here.
留在这儿，跟悍马车队撤退
Hold this corner and then exfil with the humvees.
杰利顿、史医官，跟我来，走吧
Galentine, Schmid, you're coming with me. Let's go.
你为什么要我留守？
How come I got to stay back here?
因为你很可靠
Because you're dependable.
好了
All right...
出发
...let's go!
我最恨自己很可靠
I hate being dependable, man.
你的西边有敌人接近
Juliet 25, hostiles advancing, parallel West to your position,
其中有妇女小孩
Women and children among them, Over,
靠着墙走
Hit the wall.
小心
lncoming!
手榴弹
Grenade!
快走
Go.
里头还有弟兄
We still got guys inside!
我要去坠机地点
I'll go to the crash.
你带队，我继续装载人犯
You take the rest of the team. I'll finish loading the prisoners.
不，我们要一起去坠机地点
No! We'll go to the crash site together.
守住防线，等待悍马车队
Secure the perimeter, wait for the humvees.
-收到 -跟着我
-Roger that. -Follow my lead.
中士，听到吗？
Sarg'nt, are you receiving me?
听到了，我们马上走
Yeah, I heard you. We should be leaving soon.
好了，我们要撤退
All right, we need to move out now!
人犯都上了车我就去接你们
I'll finish loading the prisoners and pick you up at the crash site!
出发吧
Let's move out!
出发了，快走
Moving out! Go!
快上车
Get in! Get in!
快点
Move!
八点钟方向
Eight o'clock!
葛姆，别靠着墙
Grimes, stay away from the walls.
你没事吧？
Grimes. You okay?
没事
Yeah!
走吧，梅道
Let's go, Maddox.
-指挥部，车队出发了 -收到
-C-2, convoy's moving out. -Roger that,
麦道，看看这些猪头
Maddox, look at these jerks! These idiots!
开快点，右转
Go, go! Right, Maddox, right!
汤比，车队走了
Twombly, the convoy is leaving!
嘿，汤比
Hey, Twombly!
什么？
What?
-他们忘了我们 -什么？
-I think they've forgotten us. -What?
算了
It doesn't matter.
敌人从四面八方赶过去，我们要赶快支援他们
63 confirm, Skinnies are moving in on all sides, They need help noW,
索马利亚人往坠机地点前进
Indigenous personnel advancing to Wolcott crash site,
请重覆
Say again. Over.
一大堆人蜂拥而上
A lot of people closing in,
第四队离那儿有多远？
How far is Chalk Four from the crash site?
-六个街口 -他们要快一点
-Six blocks, sir, -They need to haul ass.
趴下来
Get down! Get down!
史考帝，你没事吧？
Scotty, are you okay?
别回去
No, don't go back!
趴下来
Get down! Get down!
武装车
Technicals!
看到了
Got them!
六点钟方向，快走
Six o'clock! Move, move!
快…快…
Go, go, go!
快走
Go, go!
快点
Come on!
尤利，走吧
Yurek, leaving!
快点
Come on!
部队，左转
Uniform 64, left turn, Left turn,
你要告诉我在哪条街左转
Romeo 64, I need to know before I get to the goddamn street!
先停一下，情报有延误
You have to slow down. There's a delay.
侦察队要先向指挥中心报告，然后再向我下令
From the time directions are relayed from surveillance to JOC, then to me.
不能停，我们受到猛烈攻击
We can't slow down! We're taking heavy enemy fire!
我们不能停下来
We can't slow down!
我正收到侦察机的情报
Danny, I'm getting information from Orion surveillance above,
快告诉我该怎么到坠机地点
So get me my fucking directions to the crash site!
等一下，我看不到你的位置
Danny, hold on, I no longer have the best vieW of your route,
快到正确位置呀
Get your ass in the right place, goddamn it!
史崔克的车队情况如何？
What in the hell is the status of Struecker's humvees?
车队几时会回到基地？
Colonel Harrell, ETA to base, Struecker's column.
就快到了
ETA to base momentarily,
开门
Open the gate!
-把他抬下车 -来
-Get him out! Let's go! Let's go! -Come on.
小心头
Watch his head.
小心
Easy.
-贝克朋，你听到吗？ -找军医来
-Blackburn, can you hear me? -Get him to a medic.
我们在坠机地点抢救伤者
Star 41 is at the crash site to evacuate the injured, Over,
收到
Roger that,
我帮你
I got you.
小心
Easy.
杰利顿，你没事吧？
Galentine, you all right?
杰利顿、寇斯，跟我来
Galentine, Kurth, with me! Cover fire, now.
掩护他们
Full cover!
有几个人？
How many are in there?
两名驾驶阵亡，两名人员受伤
Two pilots are dead, two crew chiefs are wounded!
-他伤得很重，要把他救出来 -好，去吧
-He's hurt bad. We must get out of here. -All right. Go ahead.
这是第四小队，你在开枪吗？
26, this is 25. Is that you shooting up the technicals?
没错
This is 26. Roger that.
狄马索，到东南边建立防线
DiTomasso, take the southeast corner. We're setting up a perimeter. Over.
收到，马上赶过去
This is 26. Roger that. Moving there now.
出发
Move out!
史上尉，请回答
Captain Steele, come in.
请说
Go ahead, 25. This is 64.
有两名伤者，两名直升机驾驶都阵亡了
We got two wounded and we got both the pilots dead in the chopper!
请立刻派人接送伤兵
We need a medivac now!
救援直升机没办法降落，你要先建立防线
It's too hot to land a bird. You must secure the perimeter first. Over.
悍马车队呢？
Where are the humvees?
车队一定会到
Be advised, 25, the convoy will be there.
他们遭到猛烈攻击
They're encountering a lot of resistance. 64 out.
-快架起机关枪 -坠机地点就在前面
-Get the 50 up! -You should see the crash directly ahead.
前面只有路障
All I see is a roadblock!
我会再找另一条路
I'll have to figure out another way.
建立防线，把伤兵运走
Give me a defensive perimeter so we can load the wounded.
快开枪呀
Fire your weapon, Othic!
跟我女儿说叫她们安心
Tell my girls I'll be okay.
医官
Medic!
呼吓！
Hoo-ah!
医官…
Medic! Medic!
乔斯，帮我把他抬起来
Joyce! Joyce! Come on, help me pick him up!
快帮我们逃走，坠机地点到底在哪儿？
Get us off this fucking street! Where's the crash site? Say again.
直走两百米
Keep going straight 200 meters.
收到
Roger that.
走吧
Let's go!
快走吧
Let's go, goddamn it, let's go!
汤比，过来
Hey, Twombles. Come here.
车队不会回来了
The humvees ain't coming back, dude.
什么？
What?
我们要去找他们吗？
Were we supposed to go to them?
我以为他们要来找我们
I thought they were coming to us.
-我们应该去找他们 -该死
-I think we're supposed to go to them. -Shit.
我们赶去坠机地点
Let's go to the crash site.
好吧
Okay.
别在我耳边开枪，我听不到了
Don't fire that thing so close to my head. I can barely hear as it is.
出发
Move out.
可恶，趴下来
Shit! Get down!
我警告过你，别这么近
What did I just tell you? If you do that again--
尼森，你没事吧？
You okay? Nelson.
你没事吧？
You all right?
搜救直升机在现场进行救援
Search and rescue bird on station inserting medics.
快走
Go!
快，快
Go, go!
C-2，这是68号，我被击中了
Son of a bitch. C-2, this is 68. We've been hit.
超级68号，你的螺旋翼冒烟
Super 68, there is smoke coming from the top of your rotor.
-建议你立刻返航 -收到
-Advise you to come out now. -Roger.
最后一个人员
Dropping last man.
我看到正前方有敌人拿着火箭筒，你看到吗？
Art, I've got skinnies with RPGs at 12:00. Can you see them?
看到了，向左转九十度
Got them. Give me 90 degrees left.
我要回去了
68 coming out.
超级68号要回基地
Super 68 is out. Over.
魏肯，情况如何？
Hey, Wilkie, what's the situation in there?
两名驾驶都死了
Both pilots are dead.
我们不能移动他们
25, we can't move these guys, Matty.
他们会没命的
We'll kill them just carrying them.
-就在这儿医治 -收到
-Stabilize in here? -Roger.
我们要在这儿进行医治
Stabilize in the bird. Repeat: Stabilize in here. Over.
收到，我们掩护你们
Understood, Wilkie. We got you covered. Over.
超级64号，去替代超级61号
Super 64, come inbound and take Wolcott's position.
收到，开进中
Roger. 64 is inbound.
超级64号，你没事吧？
Super 64, you all right?
这是超级64号，我没事
This is Super 64. We're good.
确定吗？你的机身受损
You sure? You look like you got clipped pretty good.
仪表板一切正常
lnstrument panels are okay.
我们没事，机身有点晃动，不过没事
No, we're good. Got a slight vibration in the pedals, but we're good.
降落后进行检查以策安全
All right, put her down on the airfield, 64. Have it checked out just to be safe.
收到
Roger.
机身晃动得很厉害，再度检查系统
I'm getting movement in these pedals. Check the systems again.
尾部螺旋翼失效
We lost the tail rotor! It's gone!
64号要坠机
64 is going down!
64要坠机了
64 is going in hard.
我要坠机
64 going down.
我们要坠机了
We're going down.
快派史崔克的车队回去
Get Struecker's column back out there.
叫他们赶到杜伦的坠机地点
They need to get to Durant's crash site fast.
-有另一架直升机坠毁 -快去救他们
-Another bird down. -I want them out of there.
全都救出来
All of them.
史上尉，再不前进就会受困
Captain Steele, we got to move or we'll get pinned down!
我们正在尽快前进
We're moving as fast as we can.
你别管我的部队
You let me do my job and you do yours. Over.
-哎呀 -路兹，趴下来
-Fuck! Fuck! -Ruiz stay down.
-我就知道 -医官
-I fucking knew-- -Medic.
去他的！史上尉，我来对付狙击手
Fuck this! Captain Steele, I'll take out the threat in the window.
我们到灰色大楼集合
We'll rally at the gray building. Coming through.
中士
Sarg'nt!
好，走吧
All right, let's move!
掩护我
Cover me!
-快走吧 -快走
-Let's go, let's move! -Moving out.
友军
Friendly!
我是友军
Friendlies coming through!
走吧，快走
Let's go, let's go! Move up!
快…
Come on, come on!
Come on!
快走…快…
Move up! Go! Move up!
你在干什么？
What the fuck are you doing out there?
我们要赶到坠机地点
Doing my job! We got to get to that crash site!
我们一定要赶到那条街
We got to get on that street, and we got to move!
你也要跟上来
And you have got to keep up, sir!
别对我下令，中士
Don't you ever give me orders, Sergeant.
我们没办法迎敌
We are combat ineffective, understand?
太多伤兵了
We got too many wounded to move!
让我带人手绕到坠机地点
Then give me some shooters and I'll circle us to the bird.
葛姆，你在第四小队吗？
Grimes! You're with Chalk Four?
是的，长官
Yes, sir!
去跟反恐怖部队和艾中士会合
All right, hook up with Delta! Rejoin with Sergeant Eversmann.
其他的人留守这里
The rest of you, secure this position!
照顾伤兵，等待车队
Treat the wounded, we'll wait for the convoy!
然后在坠机地点会合
Then we'll rally at the crash site. Roger!
我的手下跟我走
My guys, let's go!
两名反恐怖部队狙击手，舒哈和葛顿
C-2, I have two Delta snipers, Shughart and Gordon...
自愿前往第二坠机地点
...volunteering to secure crash site two. Over.
不准，不能再牺牲另一架直升机
No, Super 62, negative that request. Can't risk another bird.
我们不能确定有人生还
We don't see anything moving down there, we don't even know if anyone's alive.
地面部队正在赶去
A ground team is being organized to go in now.
多久能赶到？
ETA on ground team? Over.
不知道，不久吧
Unknown, not long.
你们尽力从空中协助
Do what you can from the air.
大家过来
All right, gather around!
杜伦坠毁了，我们要去救他
Durant's 64 is down. We're going back in to get him!
你疯了，有人生还吗？
That's crazy. Is there anyone alive?
无所谓，绝不能抛弃同胞
Doesn't matter, no one gets left behind.
这是浪费时间
We're wasting time here.
五分钟内重新整理弹药
Refit and max out ammo and grenades, you got five!
塞斯莫，你想去哪儿？
Sizemore, where are you going?
-跟你们一起走 -你受了伤不能去
-With you guys. -Not with that cast on you're not.
好吧，去拿头盔吧
All right, all right, all right. Go get your k-pot.
说话呀
Talk to me.
我不能再回去
I can't go back out there.
汤玛斯，大家都很害怕
Thomas, everyone feels the same way you do. All right?
你现在的表现才重要
It's what you do right now that makes a difference.
这是你的决定
It's your call.
呼吓？
Hoo-ah?
呼吓
Hoo-ah.
最好把悍马车上的血迹冲掉
lt'll probably help to wash the blood out of the humvees.
史崔克中士
Sergeant Struecker!
我能去吗？
Sergeant Struecker! Can I go, Sarge?
-你有弹药吗？ -有
-You got some ammo? -Roger, Sarge!
上来吧
Hop in!
等等
Wait!
来吧，上车
Let's go, Thomas. Get in!
走哪儿？
Which way?
-那儿吧 -别这么大声
-That way, I think! -Not so fucking loud.
乖驴子
Nice donkey.
游骑兵吗？
Rangers?
你是谁？
Who?
我是尤利啦，猪头
It's Yurek! You fucking assholes!
靠
Fuck!
我们差点杀死你
Dude, we almost fucking killed you!
-你过来 -靠，你们过来
-Come to us! -Fuck you, come to me.
对不起，中士
Sorry, Sarge!
你上哪儿了？
Dude, where the fuck have you been?
你带了夜视镜吗？
Never mind, you brought NOD, right?
没有，你知道原因吗？
No, I didn't and you want to know why?
因为你说半小时就能回基地
Because you said: "You won't need that, we'll be back in a half-hour."
我不是跟你说的
Well, I wasn't saying it to you.
尼森，过来
Nelson, cover this way.
我们需要夜视镜
We'll need night vision.
你在等什么？
What's the matter with you?
他聋了，都是我害的
Oh, he's deaf. It's my fault.
-我们一定要走 -那儿
-We need to get out of here! -That way.
离坠机地点不远了，在哪儿？
We can't be far from the crash. Which way?
我以为你知道
I thought you might know.
出发吧
Let's move out.
尼森、汤比，请回答
Nelson, Twombly? Come in. Over.
这是杰利顿，车队的位置在哪里？
Nelson, Twombly, this is Galentine. We need a position of the convoy. Over.
我联络不到他们
I can't raise them, Sergeant.
我们快撤退吧
Sir, let's get the fuck out of here and evac!
-快走吧 -快回到据点
-Let's move out. -Back to the stronghold!
走吧
Come on!
地面部队占领几栋建筑物
Ground forces have occupied several buildings along Marehan Road...
但是都分散开来
...but they're all spread out.
艾中士的第四小队在威考的坠机地点建立防线
Eversmann's Chalk Four has set up a perimeter around Wolcott's crash site.
狄马索在隔壁的大楼
DiTomasso is in the adjacent structure.
史上尉的游骑兵队员在这儿，两个街口外
Captain Steele and about 40 men, Rangers, are here, a couple blocks away.
他们的情况很惨
They're banged up pretty bad.
他设立了死伤聚集点，没办法前进
He set up a casualty collection point, I don't think they'll be able to move.
桑德森中士率领手下
Sergeant Sanderson and a small Delta team...
正在赶往坠机地点
...are moving from Steele's position to the crash site as we speak.
把炮火引开
Draw off fire!
等对方装子弹就掩护我
When this asshole stops to reload, cover me!
-快 -长官
-Go! -Sir.
再来
Again!
掩护我
Loading!
继续
Keep going!
卡住了
I'm jammed!
让我来
I got it!
该死
No, shit!
火箭弹
RPG!
你没事吧？
You all right? You okay?
没事，我死不了
Yeah. I can hear bells ringing.
快，来吧
Come on! Come on!
走吧
Go!
有一群人正走向坠机地点
A crowd is advancing six, seven blocks from the crash.
舒哈和葛顿再度请求
Shughart and Gordon again request permission...
前往坠机地点进行救援
...to secure until convoy arrives. Over.
人群增加到好几百人
General, crowds are in the hundreds now.
他们看得会比我们清楚
From where they are, they can see things clearer than any of us.
他们很清楚状况
They know what they're asking.
让我跟他们说
Let me talk to them.
这是盖将军
This is Garrison.
我要确定你们很清楚状况，大声地说出来
I want to make sure that you understand what you're asking, so say it out loud.
我们要求在坠机地点建立防线
We're asking to go in and set up a perimeter until ground support arrives.
支援部队没那么快赶到
You realize that I cannot tell you when that might be, it could take a while.
-我知道 -你们还是要去？
-Roger that. -You still want to go in there?
是，长官
Yes, sir.
-哈中校 -是，将军
-Colonel Harrell? -Yes, General?
这是你的决定
It's your call.
收到
Roger that.
把他们送过去
Goffena, put them in.
该死，该死
Motherfucker. Motherfucker.
火箭弹
RPG!
建立防线
Set up your perimeter!
他身上有火箭弹
There's a fucking rocket in him, sir!
冷静点，它会爆炸，快走
Othic, calm down, goddamn it! There's live ordnance, now get out!
可恶
Son of a bitch.
把他抬起来，小心点
All right, lift him up! Lift him up! Easy, easy!
把他抬上车，很好
All right, get him in there! Good, good! Easy, easy!
快上车，开车
Get in that truck and drive.
-我受伤了 -大家都受伤了
-But I'm shot, Colonel. -Everybody's shot.
把人犯送回去
We need the prisoners! Let's go!
你要开到哈瓦迪街直走
Surveillance says to take Hawlwadig, then go straight.
我要你回头开到哈瓦迪街
McKnight, we need you to turn around and head back to Hawlwadig.
拜托，我们才从那儿来
You're shitting me! We just came through there!
一定有更好的路线
There must be a better route!
这是指挥中心的情报，你要调头回去
That's the info I'm getting from JOC, you need to turn around and head back.
收到了
Roger that. Roger that.
我不敢相信，快调头
I cannot believe this shit! Turn us around, Maddox.
他们会把我们害死
They're trying to get us fucking killed!
快开车吧
Just get it over with! Drive!
该死
Goddamn!
快走吧，开车
Get us out of here, goddamn it, drive!
快踩油门
Keep your foot on the gas!
去死
Fuck!
该死
Shit.
舒哈和葛顿下去了
C-2, Shughart and Gordon are on the deck. Over.
收到
Roger.
是友军！别开枪
Friendlies!
天啊，见到你真好
God, it's good to see you!
你也是，你伤得多重？
It's good to see you. How bad?
我的腿断了，我的背很痛
My leg's broken and my back feels kind of weird.
我们要把你救出去
We've got to get you out of here.
我把他拉出来
I'm pulling him out! Cover!
等等
Wait, l--
我把你放下来
I'm putting you down.
我们在坠机地点建立防线
C-2, we're at the 64 crash site, securing perimeter.
-你还好吧？ -我还好
-You all right? -Yeah, I'm good.
枪上膛了
You're locked and loaded.
后面有敌人就帮我们解决掉
Any skinnies come around these corners, you watch our backs.
-救援部队呢？ -我们就是了
-Where's the rescue squad? -We're it.
好了，停车
All right, stop, stop, Maddox. Stop.
可恶
Son of a bitch.
我们又回到原点
Romeo 64, we're back where we started.
弹药快用完了，大家都受伤
I'm low on ammo, I got many wounded including me...
车辆几乎毁损
...vehicles that are barely running.
好了，你就老实说吧
Okay, Danny, I need a no-b.s. assessment here.
你能到坠机地点吗？
Can you get to the crash site?
我什么也看不到
Colonel, I can't see shit.
不能
Negative.
伤兵太多，我们去也没用
With the amount of wounded we have, we'd do more harm than good.
我们要回基地补充弹药，然后再回来
We need to come back to base, rearm and regroup and then we can go back out.
收到
Roger.
把他们叫回来，叫他们快走
C-2, bring them back. Get them out of there.
收到，回基地吧
Roger. Return to base.
我们要回去了
We're going home!
走吧，左转
Let's go. Left.
下午4：54
收到了，车队要回基地
Roger that. Understand. Convoy returning to base.
-怎么回事？ -车队被叫回去了
-What's up? -They're sending them back.
车队要回基地
The convoy's headed back to base camp.
这太妙了
Oh, now that makes sense, don't it?
我们要赶紧把伤兵送回去
We need to exfil the wounded now and get out of here before it's too late!
麦中校要回基地一定有理由
If Colonel McKnight went back to base, then he had a good reason.
我们的任务不变
It changes nothing.
大伙儿听好
All right, listen up.
我们要守住这个据点
We're going to hold the perimeter and we're going to hold the strongpoint.
保留弹药，有必要才开枪
Conserve your ammo. Only shoot at what you can hit.
车队一定会回来
The convoy is going to come.
我们一定能回家
We're going to get home.
掩护我
Loading!
蓝迪，我要弹匣
Randy, I need a pistol mag!
掩护我
Loading!
最后一个弹匣
Randy, last mag!
葛顿
Gordy!
该死
Fuck!
葛顿死了，我出去拼了
Gordy is gone, man. I'll be outside.
祝好运
Good luck.
快向第十山地师求救
We need the 10th Mountain in there. Everything they got.
巴基斯坦军队、马来西亚军队 我要他们的坦克车和装甲车
Pakistanis, Malays, I want their tanks and APCs.
他们不知道我们的行动
They don't know we've gone in.
我们捅出了大篓子，整个城市都在攻击我们
We have stirred up a hornet's nest here. We're fighting the entire city.
我要每一辆军事车辆的支援，快去找，快去
I want every vehicle possible that's got 4 wheels and armor. Get everything.
我要他们我们的弟兄救出敌区
Once they've assembled, we'll move our men out of the hostile area...
安全送到巴基斯坦军队的基地
...and back to the Pakistani Stadium, the safe zone.
-快去吧 -遵命，长官
-Now, let's go. -Roger that.
联合国军队安全区
穆罕默德・艾迪德
Mohamed Farrah Aidid...
要活捉
claims this prisoner...
这名战俘
...alive!
跪下来，快点
On your knees! Get down! Get down!
撑着点，你只是大腿中弹
Stay with me. You just got a bullet in the leg.
你看到烧轮胎的黑烟吗？
See where those tires are burning? All that black smoke?
我看到了，但我到不了那儿
Roger. I can see it, but I can't get there. Over.
坠机地点离那儿只有一百米
Go 100 meters past it. That's the crash.
你不明白
Negative. You don't understand.
前面都是路障，要找另一条路
It's roadblock after roadblock. You have to find us another route. Over.
另一条路要绕过整座城市
There ain't one. The only other route is all the way around the city.
收到
Roger that.
凯罗64号，这是凯罗11号
Kilo 64, this is Kilo 11.
请准许我步行到坠机地点
Request permission to move to crash site number two on foot. Over.
好的，凯罗11号
Green light, Kilo 11.
停车，让我下去
Stop the vehicle. Let me out.
下午5：50
回去我要好好请你们喝一杯
After I'm finished with this, I'll whip you boys up some margaritas.
玛格丽特调酒，不加盐
The usual. Blended, no salt.
这是凯罗12号，我们一定要移动位置
This is Kilo 12. We've got to change our position. Over.
艾中士，请回答
Eversmann, come in.
艾中士
Eversmann.
-收到，你是谁？ -桑中士
-Roger who is this? -Sanderson.
千万别向东边开枪，我们要过去
Do not-- I say again, do not fire to the east. We are coming to you.
了解
Understood.
狄马索在东南角
DiTomasso and his men are on the southeast corner.
你们要占领东北角
We need you on the northeast building.
收到，没问题
Roger. We'll take it.
小心敌人，他们在屋顶
Watch out for skinnies. They're on the rooftops.
他们的祷告就快结束了
They're in prayer but not for much longer.
别向东边开火
Hold your fire to the east.
艾中士，这是尤利
Eversmann? It's Yurek.
尼森和汤比跟我在一起
I got Nelson and Twombly with me.
我们看到直升机，你在哪里？
We got the chopper in sight. Where are you?
我们在西南角，你没事吧？
We're on the southwest corner. Where have you been? Are you okay?
没事
Yeah.
别开枪，我们来了
Hold your fire. We're coming in.
我们要走了
We got to go.
听好，尤中士要先跑
Shawn, listen! Sergeant Yurek's going to run first.
等他过了马路，就会转过头掩护你
When he gets across the street, he'll turn around and cover you as you run.
听清楚了，你到了那儿也要掩护我
Listen closely. When you get there, you'll turn around and cover me, okay?
你不能直接跑去找艾中士
You won't just run to Eversmann's position.
你要停下来掩护我
You're going to stop and you are going to cover me.
你一定要搞清楚这点
It's important you understand that.
好了吗？
Okay, you ready?
好了
Yeah, I guess.
-别忘了 -什么？
-Don't forget. -What?
别忘了我
Don't forget.
我看到他们了，他们来了
I got them in my sight, Sarg'nt. They're coming up on the west gate.
我看到了
I see them.
出去吧
Let's move out.
你能掩护我们吗？
Can you cover us, Sergeant?
没问题
We got you.
尼森
Nelson!
可恶
Fuck!
汤比
Twombly!
史密斯，不！
Smith! No!
你没事吧？
You all right?
快弄掉，快点
Get it off of me!
快呀
Get it off!
快
Come on, man. Come on.
医官，快来帮史密斯
Doc! Need some help with Smith here!
我的腿
My leg! My leg!
我帮你
Come on, Jamie, I got you!
抬起来，1、2、3
Up, one, two, three.
-你没事了 -用力压他的伤口
-You're all right. -I need some pressure on this wound.
我的右腿
My right thigh!
用力压
Pressure, yeah.
-我的蛋蛋还在吧？ -还在啦
-Are my balls okay? -You still have your balls.
我需要帮手
I need more men in here.
汤比、尼森
Twombly! Nelson!
-压住他 -真是…
-Put him down. -Oh, man, that really....
-真是很痛 -直接施加压力
-lt really hurts! -Direct pressure on that.
没事的
It's okay, it's okay.
-让我看 -好了
-Let me see it! -All right.
让我看看
All right, let me get a look at that.
该死
Oh, shit!
Oh, fuck!
-怎么回事？ -没事
-What the fuck was that? -It's all right.
按住，我要立刻送他回去
Hold that down. I need a medivac now.
杰利顿
Fuck. Galentine!
没事
It's all right.
杰利顿，快帮我接史上尉
Galentine! Get me Captain Steele!
-你还好吧？ -请回答
-Sarg'nt Ruiz, how you doing? -Juliet 64, come in. Over.
他们不会来接我们了
They're not going to come and get us. They're not going to come for us.
给我闭嘴，振作点
I need you to suck it up, Sarg'nt. I need you to focus.
-你办得到吗？ -请回答
-Can you do that? -Juliet 64, come in. Over.
你能开枪吗？
Now, can you hold your weapon?
能
Yes, sir.
谁敢闯进来就让他吃子弹
Anybody comes through that door gets two in the chest and one in the head.
-明白吗？ -我可以打仗
-You understand? -I'm still in the fight, sir.
史上尉，请派人接送伤兵
Captain Steele, I need a medivac in here now!
-史下士中弹 -等一下
-Corporal Smith has been hit! -Hold on, 25.
我可以打仗
Still in the fight.
他伤得很重
He's hurt pretty bad.
我们也有伤兵，你要留在原地
25, we got wounded too. You'll have to maintain your situation, over.
他再不进医院就会没命
If he doesn't get help in a half-hour, he's in trouble!
C-2，这是部队
C-2, this is 64.
第四小队需要医疗救援
Requesting a medivac for a critically wounded at Chalk Four's location. Over.
第四小队请求医疗救援
Command, Chalk Four is requesting medivac.
战况激烈，不能冒险
Can't risk it. It's still too hot.
我们不能派出医疗救援，撑下去
Captain, we cannot send in medivac at this time. Sit tight. Over.
25号，这是64号， 没有医疗救援，战况太激烈
25, this is 64. Negative on the medivac. It's not possible.
不能再冒险派救援直升机 你们要撑下去
JOC cannot risk another bird. You'll just have to hold on.
让我来
All right. I got him.
直接压在伤口上
I want direct pressure on the wound.
你不会有事的
It's going to be all right.
这是我的直升机
I think this is mine!
这是凯罗11号，我到了杜伦的坠机地点
This is Kilo 11. I'm at the Durant crash site.
收到
Roger that.
第二坠机地点安全
Crash site two secured.
柯中校找你
Lieutenant Colonel Cribbs for you, sir.
柯中校？
Cribbs?
第十山地师基地
-They're still debating the route. -How long?
-他们还在讨论路线 -还要多久？
At least a couple of hours.
至少两个小时
来不及了
We haven't got that long, Joe.
巴基斯坦将军说我们事先没有通知他们
Pakistani General says, since we didn't deign to inform him of the raid...
动员第十山地师要花点时间
...it'll take some time to mobilize the 10th Mountain and 100 vehicles.
你告诉他
You tell the general this:
我了解，但是我也要提醒他
I understand, but it is my duty to remind him...
我的手下被武装民兵团团包围
...that my men are surrounded by thousands of armed Somali militia.
我们必须立刻把他们救出敌区
It's imperative that we move them out of the hostile area and into the safe zone.
我需要他的帮助
I need his help now.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
杜伦
Durant.
迈可杜伦
Michael Durant.
是的
Yes.
你是杀我同胞的游骑兵队员？
You are the Ranger who kills my people?
我不是，我是驾驶员
I'm not a Ranger. I'm a pilot.
没错
That's right.
美国人不抽烟了
None of you Americans smoke anymore.
你们都过着无趣的生活
You all live long, dull, uninteresting lives.
你为什么要抓我？
What do you want with me?
你们手上有我们的人质
You have taken hostages.
我们手上有你
We have you.
美国政府才不会跟你谈判
My government will never negotiate for me.
那么我就跟你谈判吧
Then perhaps you and I can negotiate, huh?
我们都是军人
Soldier to soldier.
我不是指挥官
I'm not in charge.
当然不是，你们能杀人却不能谈判
Course not. You have the power to kill, but not negotiate.
在索马利亚，杀人就是谈判
In Somalia, killing is negotiation.
你们真的以为抓到艾迪德将军
Do you really think if you get General Aidid...
我们就会放下武器
...we will simply put down our weapons...
接受美式民主
...and adopt American democracy?
或是停止杀戮吗？
That the killing will stop?
我只知道没有胜利就没有和平
We know this: Without victory, there can be no peace.
杀戮永远不会停止
There will always be killing, you see?
这就是我们的方法，迈可杜伦，我们不会抛弃你
This is how things are in our world.
迈可杜伦，我们不会抛弃你
Mike Durant, we won't leave you behind.
换你来，用双手按住
You got to take over from me. Both hands.
伤口在股动脉，但是我看不到
It's the femoral artery, but I can't see it.
它一定缩进骨盆
Which means that it's retracted up into the pelvis.
我必须把它夹住，这样才能止血
I have to find it and clamp it. It's the only way to stop the bleeding.
麻醉剂用完了
I got no more lVs.
所以我要你帮忙，好吗？
So, I'm going to need you to assist. Okay?
好
Yeah, yeah.
听好，我要做一件事
Now listen, Jamie. I got to do something, it's going to hurt.
你会很痛，不过我必须帮助你
I got to cause you more pain, but I have to do it to help you.
你懂吗？
All right, you understand?
-吗啡 -不行
-Morphine. -I can't.
那会降低你的心跳
lt'll lower your heart rate too far. I'm sorry.
汤比，抓住他的手
Twombly, why don't you take his hands?
把伤口撑开，压住他的大腿
Hold the wound open, keep pressure on the top of the leg.
尤利，帮我拿手电筒
Yurek, take the feet and a flashlight.
我数到三
On my count.
准备好了
All right, Jamie. All right.
一、二
One. Two.
三
Three.
等等，摸到了
Wait, wait. Okay. I feel it.
我摸到脉搏
I feel the pulse.
我找到了
I got it. I got it.
找到了…
I got it, yeah. I got it.
-找到了？ -找到了
-I got it. -You got it?
夹子
Clamp?
钳住了
I got it clamped.
-拿住 -好
-Hold it. -Got it.
这里，抓住
Here, grab it.
-它破了 -我抓住了
-It's tearing. -I got it.
-它又缩回去了 -抓住它
-Doc, it's going back in! -Hold it!
破了
It's tearing!
-出来，撑开伤口 -撑开了
-Okay. Get out. Hold the wound. -Okay, I'm holding.
把手拿开
Move your hand.
怎么了？
What?
治好了吗？
Fix it?
对，治好了
Yeah, yeah. We got it.
你在干什么？
What the hell are you doing?
关键是磨咖啡豆，不能磨得太细或太粗
It's all in the grind, Sarg'nt. Can't be too fine, can't be too coarse.
葛姆，你都弄好了
Grimesy, you are squared away.
来一杯热腾腾的咖啡吧
Sarg'nt, how would you like a nice hot cup of Joe?
黄金海岸口味
Gold Coast blend.
坐下来，我看你的伤口
Sit down. I want to take a look at that foot.
-这不算什么 -来
-No, it's not a problem. -Come on.
-他们从哪儿把你找来？ -办公桌后面
-Where the hell did they find you? -Behind a desk.
是真的，我没开玩笑
No, really. What, you think I'm kidding?
-有人受伤吗？ -没有
-ls anybody hit? -We're good!
你们没事吧？
You all right?
没事
Yeah!
大家都没事吧？
Is everybody all right?
没事
Yeah!
火箭弹
lncoming!
继续开火，快点
Keep firing...faster!
狄马索中弹，快救他
DiTomasso's hit! Pull him out!
这是凯罗11号
Ranger here. This is Kilo 11.
我们在东南角，你是谁？
Chalk Four. We're at the southeast corner of the crash. Who's this?
胡特，我带了三名同胞来
This is Hoot. I'm coming with three friendlies.
请掩护我
I need cover fire. Over.
收到，凯罗11号，停火，反恐怖部队来了
Roger, Kilo 11. Hold your fire! Deltas coming in.
停火
Hold your fire! Hold your fire!
地面部队要用红外线求生灯做记号
Ground personnel will have to mark target positions with infrared strobes.
派出攻击直升机向敌人扫射
Get little birds on strafing runs and keep them going all night long.
如果控制不了状况
If we don't hold back this city...
我们的死伤会很惨重
...we'll have a 100 caskets to fill by morning.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
第一坠机地点的地面部队
Colonel Harrell, ground personnel at crash site one...
要用红外线求生灯在目标上做记号
...will have to mark the target with infrared strobes to prep for air strike.
巴基斯坦体育场
麦中校
McKnight.
第十山地师的支援部队就够了
Between the 10th Mountain and U.N., we got enough personnel, okay?
你们不必再回去
Danny, you guys do not have to go back out again.
晚上11:23
我不能死在这儿
I can't die here, man.
你不会死的，你不会死
You're not going to die, all right? You're not going to die.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你不必道歉
You don't have anything to be sorry for.
你救了汤比，你干得很好
You saved Twombly. You did perfect.
汤比，你没事吧？
You okay, Twombs?
我没事
Yeah, I'm okay, Jamie.
你是个好军人
You did what you were trained to do.
你应该感到自傲
You should be proud of that.
你要感到骄傲
Be proud of that.
-小艾 -什么事？
-Ev? -Yeah.
帮我一个忙
Do me a favor.
跟我父母说我今天很英勇
You tell my parents that I fought well today.
我也尽了全力
And that I fought hard.
你要亲口跟他们说
You're going to tell them yourself, okay?
听到吗？
Do you hear me?
好吗？
All right?
-悍马车队来了吗？ -他们来了
-Are the humvees here? -They're coming, Jamie.
来了
They're coming.
你要撑下去
You just got to hang in there a little bit.
-再多撑一下子 -小意思
-You hold on for just a little bit. -I can.
我行的
I can.
没问题…
It's nothing.
没问题
-没问题 -没问题
-It's nothing. -It's nothing.
没问题
Nothing.
可恶
Oh, shit.
压住伤口
Hold the wound.
医官
Doc.
没事
It's okay.
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
我们需要弹药
We need the ammo.
你已经尽了力
You did all you could here.
他们应该派直升机救援
They should've sent a medivac.
它一定会被击落
Right now we'd be out there defending another crashed chopper.
更多人会受伤
More men would get torn up.
也许吧
Maybe.
别想那么多
See, you're thinking. Don't.
你不能决定谁受伤
Because, Sergeant, you can't control who gets hit or who doesn't.
或是谁从直升机上摔落
Who falls out of a chopper or why.
这是战争，你也无能为力
It ain't up to you. It's just war.
史密斯还是死了
Yeah, well, Smith's still dead.
-都是因为贝克朋摔下来 -你想这么多也没用
-This all happened because Blackburn fell. -Should have, could have, don't matter.
以后你有的是时间去想
You'll get plenty of time to think about all that later. Believe me.
你把弟兄们带到这儿
Sergeant, you got your men this far.
你已经尽了全力
You did it right today.
你要想该怎么把他们救出去
You need to start thinking about getting these men out of here.
走吧
Well, shall we?
我要四个人守住这角落
I need four guys in this corner now!
火箭弹
RPG!
我准备进行机关枪扫射
This is Barber 52 in position for gun run.
老天爷，你看看
Jesus Christ. Look at that.
我看到了，你就在我上方
This is 25! I can see you. You're right above me.
我分不出谁是敌谁是友，状况太混乱了
Eversmann, I can't tell who's who down there. Too much activity.
我会用红外线求生灯做记号
I'll mark the target with a strobe! Over.
收到
Roger that.
看到吗？
You see it?
我什么也看不到
Nah, I can't see shit.
-我要丢到屋顶 -你需要帮忙
-I'm putting it on the roof. -You're going to need help!
掩护我
Cover me.
我数到三就开枪掩护他
Okay, guys, we're going to lay down some cover fire for him on three!
好了吗？
Ready?
一
One.
二
Two.
三，开枪
Three. Go!
我看到目标了，准备进行扫射
I got your position. I got the target. We're inbound and hot.
C-2，弹药用完了，请求返回基地
C-2, miniguns dry. Request permission to return to base. Rearm. Over.
收到，第二队前往支援
Roger that. Second team inbound. Your station.
四分钟后抵达
On your location, four minutes.
车队来了，准备走了
All right, they're here. Get the wounded ready to move.
掩护我们
Lay down some cover fire!
我早就听到你们了
I thought I heard a noise out here!
-准备好，我们要出发 -是，长官
-Load up. We're getting out of here. -Yes, sir.
25号，这是64号，救援车队出发了五分钟后抵达
25, this is 64. The rescue column's here and will be with you in about 5 minutes.
准备撤退
Prepare your men for exfil.
收到，收到了
Yeah, roger that, sir! Roger that!
救援车队五分钟后就到
Five minutes! The convoy is going to be here in five minutes!
我要弹匣，我用完了
I need a mag! Eversmann, I'm out!
最后一个
My last one!
清晨2:05
救援车队来了
The convoy is here!
艾中士，听说你们要搭便车
Sergeant Eversmann. I heard you guys needed a lift!
是的，长官
Yes, sir!
把伤兵抬上来
Bring your wounded and start loading them up!
我扶你
Hey, I got you. I got you.
没关系，我想用走的
It's okay. I want to walk.
我也一样，走吧
Yeah, I would too. Let's go!
出发
Move!
找到驾驶尸体就回体育场
We get the pilots' bodies out, and then we go to the stadium.
车上没有地方了
We're running out of room around here.
尽量挤一挤
Cram into every possible space.
第十山地师出动装甲车，保护我们从敌区撤退
Okay, 10th Mountain provides security for armor, walks us out of the hot zone.
第十山地师？
10th Mountain? No.
我们游骑兵的人可以殿后
Sir, with respect, my Rangers can provide rear security.
我们走出敌区然后再坐车
We'll walk you out of the hot zone, then we'll jump on the last few vehicles.
好，出发吧
Okay, let's get out of here.
走吧
Let's go.
-好了吗？ -来吧
-All right, you got him? -Yeah, come on.
来
Come on!
目标太明显了，快走吧
These things are fucking bullet magnets. Come on, let's go!
我要接到命令才能走
We go when I'm ordered to, soldier.
小心点
Careful.
小心
Easy. Go easy.
Easy.
上校，怎么回事？
Colonel, what is going on down there?
他们绕着尸体拆解驾驶舱
They're dismantling the entire cockpit around the body.
还要多久？我要你老实说
How long is it going to take? I need an honest, no-shit assessment.
说不准
They can't say!
丹尼
Danny...
绝对不能抛弃同胞
...no one gets left behind.
你明白吗？
You understand me, son?
明白
Yes, General.
你要尽一切可能
Do what you have to do.
遵命
Roger.
-快点，把他抬出来 -好了
-Come on. Bring him through. -I got him.
-把伤兵救出来 -遵命
-Get all his gear. Get the wounded out. -Got you, sir!
10月4日，星期一，早上5：45
-快走 -好
-Move! -Got you!
快走
Move out! Move out! Let's go!
该死
Fuck!
要爆炸了
Fire in the hole!
-快走 -走吧
-Let's go! Move! -Let's go!
-快开门，我们要上去 -挤不下了，坐到车顶
-Open the hatch! We got men back here! -No room here! Go on the roof!
怎么回事？
What's going on?
-车顶？ -我才不坐车顶
-The roof? -I'm not getting on no fucking roof!
没地方坐了
No, no, it's full.
前进吧，用装甲车当掩护
We're running out. Keep moving. Use the vehicles as cover.
走吧
Move it! Let's go!
等一下
All right, hold it up. Hold it up.
-出发吧 -走
-Move! -Go! Move!
走
Go!
趴下来
Get down! Get down!
让开
Get down, lady!
我没子弹了
I'm out of ammo!
桑德森，我没子弹了
Sanderson, I'm out of ammo!
别拿枪
Don't you do it.
-你在干嘛？ -别开枪
-What are you doing? -Don't you damn do it.
走吧
Kurth, let's go!
小心点
Easy.
可恶
Ah, shit.
子弹错过你的颈静脉，别动
Bullet missed your jugular by about three millimeters. Don't move.
快点啦
Hurry up, hurry up.
咖啡没了，我替你倒了茶
Little short on coffee, but I got you some tea.
你还好吧？
How you doing, soldier?
我没有感觉
Can't feel a thing.
替他量脉搏
Take his pulse.
中士
Hey, Sarg'nt.
队长
Captain.
你还好吧？
Lorenzo. How you doing?
子弹穿过去，医官说我过两天就没事
It went in and out, so the medic said I should be okay in a couple of days.
真是好消息
That's great news.
我们要继续打吗？
Are we going after them?
当然了，我们要重新整队
You bet your ass we will. We got to regroup.
别把我留下来
Don't go out there without me.
别丢下我就回去
Don't go back out there without me.
我还能打仗
I can still do my job.
好好休息吧
You get some rest now, okay?
你要回去？
You're going back in?
战区还有弟兄
There are still men out there.
该死
Goddamn.
我每次回家
When I go home...
他们都问我
...and people ask me:
胡特，你为什么从军？
"Hey, Hoot, why do you do it, man?
难道你是打仗打上瘾吗？
"Why? You some kind of war junkie?"
我一句话也不说
I won't say a goddamn word.
为什么？
Why?
他们不会懂
They won't understand.
他们不懂我们干嘛打仗
They won't understand why we do it.
我们是为了同胞弟兄拼命
They won't understand it's about the men next to you.
就这么简单
And that's it.
很简单
That's all it is.
想都别想，我习惯单枪匹马
Don't even think about it, all right? I'm better on my own.
星期一，又是一周的开始
We started a whole new week. It's Monday.
贝克朋问我
I was talking to Blackburn the other day...
什么改变了？我们为什么要回家？
...and he asked me, "What changed? Why are we going home?"
我说什么都没变
And I said, "Nothing. "
但这不是实话，一切都变了
But that's not true, you know. I think everything's changed.
我也变了
I know I've changed.
之前有一个朋友问我
A friend of mine asked me before I got here....
那是在我们被派来之前
It was when we were all shipping out.
他问我
He asked me:
你为什么要去打别人的仗？
"Why are you going to fight somebody else's war?
你自以为是英雄吗？
"What, do y'all think you're heroes?"
当时我不知道该说什么
I didn't know what to say at the time...
现在我的答案是不
...but if he asked me again, I'd say no.
我不想当英雄
I'd say there's no way in hell.
没有人想当英雄
Nobody asks to be a hero.
只是有时候时势造英雄
It just sometimes turns out that way.
我会去找你的父母
I'll talk to your ma and pa when I get home, okay?
一千多名索马利亚人死亡
十九名美军阵亡
我的爱，你会坚强地活下去
My love, you are strong and you will do well in life.
我爱你和我的孩子
I love you and my children deeply.
每一天都会成长茁壮
Today and tomorrow, let each day grow and grow.
保持笑容，千万别被困境打倒
Keep smiling and never give up, even when things get you down.
最后，我的爱
So, in closing, my love...
今晚替我哄我的孩子入睡
...tonight, tuck my children in bed warmly.
跟他们说我爱他们
Tell them I love them. Then hug them for me...
替爸爸亲吻他们道晚安
...and give them both a kiss good night for Daddy.
反恐怖部队葛中士及舒中士
是越战之后第一次获追赠荣誉勋章的士兵
迈可杜伦被囚禁十一天后被释
两星期后，柯林顿总统从索马利亚撤军
威廉盖瑞森少将为这次突击行动负起全责
1996年8月2日，穆罕默德・艾迪德遭刺杀 隔天盖瑞森少将退役
Subtitulado por _Hosen_ hosen@fibertel.com.ar
Subresync by Chros69